

# HILMAN FIRDAUS, S.KOM

GITHUB: hilman-firdd (Hilman Firdaus) (github.com)

GITLAB : <a href="https://gitlab.com/hilman-firdd">https://gitlab.com/hilman-firdd</a>
LINKEDIN. : <a href="mailto:(24) Hilman Firdaus | LinkedIn">(24) Hilman Firdaus | LinkedIn</a>
Portfolio. : <a href="mailto:portfolio.hilfideveloper.com">portfolio.hilfideveloper.com</a>
EMAIL : <a href="mailto:hilmanfirdaus48@gmail.com">hilmanfirdaus48@gmail.com</a>

WA/TELP. : 081914209656

# Summary

Graduated from Nurtanio University, with cumlaude predicate, GPA 3.69. also expertise with almost 4 years of experience as a Quality Assurance Engineer in a company which requires me to remain in the corridor of contributing my skills towards technology progress in the software industry internationally.finance or

# **Education**

Bachelor Degree - Engineering Informatics, NURTANIO UNIVERSITY - Bandung (2017 -2021). GPA 3.69

# **Work Experiences**

#### PT Astra Internasional Tbk (November-Desember 2023)

Astra offers a variety of choices and the latest models of motorized vehicles according to consumer needs. Astra produces, assembles, distributes and has a dealer network for Toyota, Daihatsu, Isuzu, Peugeot, UD Trucks and Honda motorbikes. Astra also produces and is a retailer of BMW and Lexus cars.

Project Auto2000 (November-Desember 2023)

- Update bugs using Azzure Tools
- Carry out performance tests using the Jmeter tool
- Creating test scenarios using Excel spreadsheets based on FSD and Figma UI/UX notions
- SIT, UAT, Regression manual testing, based on desktop, CMS and Mobile Responsive categories
- Testing Automation tools Katalon Studio
- SEO testing using gtmetrix, Rich results test, lighthouse, seo meta and disable javascript

## PT Moladin Digital Indonesia (April-Oktober 2023)

Moladin has built the entrepreneurial spirit of its agents with its fast-growing network, involving more than 100,000 agents and dealers by creating a comprehensive digital automotive platform and providing best-inclass training, assistance and support.

My Responsibilities:

- Developing and maintaining test plans and test cases for software applications.
- Executing manual tests to ensure the quality and functionality of software applications.
- Identifying, troubleshooting, and documenting defects in software applications.

- Working closely with developers to resolve defects and improve the quality of the software.
- Collaborating with other QA engineers to review and improve the testing process.
- Create testing API with Postman
- Do research Automation using Playwright
- Report test ops in Allure

### PT Hilfi Dev Technology (September 2022 - Mei 2023)

**SpeedCash** (Desember-Januari 2022)

is an application, for those of you who want to travel by plane, making a plane ticket reservation in advance is the best way to secure the departure or schedule you want.

My Responsibilities:

- Do Perform API Testing on Microservices/Rest API.
- Define, Analyze Requirement for implement to Test Scenario in Testrail or Spreadsheet
- Do research Automation using Katalon(intermediete) & Cypress
- Monitoring Story/task/bugs using Jira & Trello.
- Do Perform Functional Testing in Website, Progresive Web Application, Mobile Applications

## **Anaonline.id Management system** (Januari-Maret 2023)

is an application for managing special systems for youth exactly, such as membership and special applications

My Responsibilities:

- Do Perform API Testing on Microservices/Rest API.
- Define, Analyze Requirement for implement to Test Scenario in Spreadsheet
- Do research Automation using Webriver.io typescript mocha & chai
- Monitoring Story/task/bugs using Gitlab and Circle Cl.
- Do Perform Functional Testing in Website, Progresive Web Application, Mobile Applications

#### Simasis, Management system (April-Mei 2023)

is an application for managing special systems for youth exactly, such as membership and special applications

My Responsibilities:

- Define, Analyze Requirement for implement to Test Scenario in Spreadsheet
- Do research Automation using Selenium javascript, mocha & chai
- Monitoring Story/task/bugs using Gitlab and Circle Cl.
- Do Perform Functional Testing in Website
- Do Perform function Testing third party, in Midtrans.

# PT Telekomunikasi Indonesia (Juni 2019 - Agustus 2022)

#### **Dunia Games** (Juni-Aqustus)

is a site that provides various user needs related to games offered by PT. Cellular Telecommunications (TELKOMSEL). Access to Dunia Games can be done through the website <a href="www.duniagames.co.id">www.duniagames.co.id</a> and applications available on the Android OS and Apple iOS platforms on your smartphone. The terms & conditions stipulated below givern the use of Dunia Games, both the use the <a href="www.duniagames.co.id">www.duniagames.co.id</a> website and the Dunia Games Applications.

My Responsibilities:

- Perform automated testing web application project.
- Perform automated testing mobile application (native & hybrid)
- Raise bugs & feedback to engineer teams in our sprint development

- Review requirement & spesification for create acceptance testing in User Story
- Perform Automation Testing in API, web, mobile Using Katalon & Postman
- Writing & Review acceptance test in User Journey
- Perform E2E Testing & Regression Testing in our project
- Report tase case in jira tools

### **MEA & MEC** (Agustus-Oktober)

is application to manage and monitor field workers, with a cloud-based mobile application to manage and monitor field workers, and improve communication between workers wherever they are using field force management.

### My Responsibilities:

- Perform automated testing web application project.
- Perform automated testing mobile application (web automation)
- Raise bugs & feedback to engineer teams in our sprint development
- Review requirement & spesification for create acceptance testing in User Story
- Perform Automation Testing in API, web Using Katalon
- Writing & Review acceptance test in User Journey
- Report tase case in jira tools

#### 99Usahaku (November-Januari)

99% of My Business was developed to support the growth of Small and Medium Enterprises (SMEs) in Indonesia. SMEs can use 99% Usahaku as a platform for sales.

#### My Responsibilities:

- Perform automated testing web application project.
- Perform automated testing mobile application (web automation)
- Raise bugs & feedback to engineer teams in our sprint development
- Review requirement & spesification for create acceptance testing in User Story
- Perform Automation, web Using Katalon
- Writing & Review acceptance test in User Journey
- Report tase case in jira tools

### **FUT Home LTE(My Orbit)** (Februari-April)

Telkomsel Orbit is an all-digital home internet service provider in Indonesia that uses WiFi modem devices.

#### My Responsibilities:

- Perform automated testing web application project.
- Perform automated testing mobile application (web automation)
- Raise bugs & feedback to engineer teams in our sprint development
- Review requirement & spesification for create acceptance testing in User Story
- Perform Automation, web Using Katalon
- Writing & Review acceptance test in User Journey
- Report tase case in jira tools

# **Key Skills and Expertise**

#Katalon #Cypress #Javascript #Selenium #Typescript #Java #E2ETesting #PostgresSql

#Jira #Agile #RegressionTesting #SIT-UAT-REGRESI-SANITY #SmokeTesting #LoadTesting

#jMeter #WebDriver #ApiTesting #Bitbucket #AllureTestOps #Playwright #MobileTesting

#blackBox #whiteBox #confluenceDokumentation #excelReport #SDLC #STLC #pipeline

#Jenkins #gitlabCICD

# Certification

(24) Licenses & certifications | Hilman Firdd | LinkedIn

# Languages

English

Arab

Indonesia